On the 5th, the first boat to open the course to Mount Geumgang
在5日开启金刚山航线的第一艘船
was Bongraeho.
蓬莱号启航
Hyundai decided to put 800 passengers who reserved a trip to Mount Geumgang
800名预定前往金刚山观光的乘客 遭遇蓬莱号延期
that had been postponed on Bongraeho.
现代公司决定搭载这批乘客
Well, I can't say that for sure. But I…
其实我也不敢肯定 不过我…
They murdered and dismembered a member of their gang.
他们谋杀并肢解了一名帮派成员
And they also ate up the intestines.
随后竟分食他的肠子
This grotesque murder shocked the public.
这起怪诞谋杀案让民众大为震惊
Reporter Kim Sang-gi from Daejeon Broadcasting will continue.
大田广播记者金尚奇继续为您播报
Six members of the so-called Hero Gang…
所谓的英雄帮六名成员…
SHOW THE RIGHT PATH AND PROTECT WITH WARMTH
（用正道感化 用爱心守护）
REFORM OF HOPE FOR THE PEOPLE
（用希望改造）
VISITATION REQUEST FORM
（探访申请表）
NAME: YANG YONG-CHUL
（姓名：梁龙哲）
VISITATION REQUEST COUNTER
（探访申请台）
Okay.
好了
Inmate 3585.
3585号犯人
He refused the visitation request.
他拒绝了探访请求
-Have a good day. -Thank you.
-辛苦了 -好
Inmate 3585.
3585号犯人
He refused the visitation request.
他拒绝了探访请求
Detective, why don't you send some money to his commissary account?
警官 不如试试给他的 监狱商店账户充点钱
Come on.
真是
What's this about?
这是干吗？
You don't even know who I am. Why did you refuse to see me?
你连我是谁都不知道 为什么拒绝见我？
Well…
因为…
There's no one who would visit me.
没人想见我
And whenever someone came to see me, it was never good news.
每次有人想见我 都没好事
Why did you think he wasn't the culprit?
你为什么觉得他不是凶手？
That guy isn't the culprit.
那家伙不是凶手
I see. You have a good memory, Detective.
原来如此 你记性真好 刑警
But you kept coming here because of that?
你就是因为那个才坚持过来吗？
That's odd.
真奇怪
I want to know
我想知道
why you thought he wasn't the culprit.
你为什么觉得他不是凶手
Why do you want to know?
你为什么想知道？
You won't tell me?
你不想告诉我吗？
Why should I tell you that?
我为什么要告诉你？
You don't need money?
你不想要钱吗？
Well…
好吧…
I can tell just by looking at their eyes. Here's a thing about hunches.
我从他们的眼神就能看出来了 这就是直觉
Detectives aren't the only ones who have them.
不是只有刑警才有这种直觉
He stripped the girl naked.
你们不是说他把那女孩脱光
And he killed her in the heat of the moment.
一时冲动把她杀了
If that's the case, why strip her naked?
如果是这样 为什么要脱她的衣服？
And she was his girlfriend.
而且她是他女友
Allegedly, he killed her in the heat of the moment.
据说他是冲动杀人
They must have been in love, right?
他们肯定很相爱 对吧？
Even if he killed her, it was a mistake.
就算他杀了她 也是一个错误
Or an accident?
或者是失手？
Okay. Let's call it an accident.
好 假设是失手
Then he would have dressed her if she was naked.
那么如果她没穿衣服 他会把她衣服穿上
That's what a normal guy would do.
这才是正常人会做的事
Only those who have killed before
只有那种惯犯
would strip their victims naked.
才会把受害者脱光了
That's my point.
这是我的看法
You know what habits are, right?
你知道什么叫习惯吧？
Old habits die hard.
旧习难改
And you end up doing these habits
你会在无意间做出那些
before you realize it.
习惯性行为
What does that have to do with this case?
那和这个案子有什么关系？
When I was a kid,
我小时候
my father always beat me up during our meals.
我爸喜欢在吃饭的时候打我
Do you know why he beat me up?
你知道他为什么打我吗？
Because I always left a spoonful of rice instead of finishing it.
因为我总会剩最后一口饭
It's odd. I just didn't want to eat the last spoonful of rice.
很奇怪 我就是不想吃最后一口饭
Eating the last spoonful made me feel…
吃掉最后一口饭会让我觉得…
like I was losing my spirit.
自己的灵魂出窍了
That was an exaggeration.
说得有点夸张
Anyway, he beat me up for leaving rice because it'd be bad luck.
总之他因为我剩饭不吉利就打我
But I still don't finish my food.
可我还是不会把饭吃光
There's no one who would beat me
就算现在没有人
for leaving the last spoonful now.
会因为我剩饭打我
Let me sum it up.
总之
No matter how meticulously you plan something,
不管你计划得多么严谨
your habits come out like second nature.
习惯就像老朋友一样总会暴露出来
That's my point.
这就是我的看法
I'm sure there was a reason behind stripping her.
我敢肯定脱她衣服是有原因的
He had to strip her to get off.
他一定要把她衣服脱了心里才舒坦
And whoever did that…
不管是谁干的…
is the real culprit.
那才是真正的凶手
Just like how I had to leave the last spoonful of rice to be satisfied
像我一样 一定要剩最后一口饭才能满足
no matter how much my father beat me up.
不管我爸打我多狠
I bet I'm right about this.
我肯定猜对了
Detective Song Ha-young.
宋霞永刑警
-Gosh. Again? -His MO is bothering me.
-真是的 又来了？ -我觉得他的作案手法有问题
I'm sure it's related to Won Mal-sook's case in Uyeong-dong.
肯定和右营洞元末淑案有关
What MO?
什么作案手法？
It's the way she was killed.
就是她被杀的方式
She was also found naked without any signs of sexual assault.
她也是一丝不挂但没有强奸痕迹
He did that to humiliate the victims.
他这么做是为了羞辱受害者
The case is closed. Stop causing trouble.
案子已经结了 别找事了
It's not a request. I'm warning you.
这不是请求 是警告
Hey. Answer me.
喂 回答我
Don't do anything.
别瞎搞
I warned you!
我警告你
Hey! Darn it.
喂 该死
WON MAL-SOOK'S RESIDENCE
（元末淑的住处）
Signs of forced entry.
有被强行侵入的痕迹
No numbers.
没有数字
SERVICE, ORDER
（服务 秩序）
-Here, this is for you. -Thank you.
-来 给你 -谢谢你
My gosh, you must have a sweet tooth.
天啊 看来你喜欢吃甜食
Yes.
是的
All the detectives at Dongbu Police Station are busy,
东部警察局的刑警们都很忙
so we thoroughly investigated the case, but…
所以我们就彻底 调查了这起案子 不过…
I'm sure you couldn't catch that petty thief.
你们肯定没抓到那个狡猾的小偷
Like you suggested last time,
根据你上次的建议
we questioned all the delivery guys who work in the area
我们询问了当地所有外卖员
but couldn't track him down.
可是没查出他来
I think it made him nervous though. Things have been quiet since then.
我觉得他肯定是紧张了 从那时过来一直都很平静
We've further enhanced patrols in the area.
我们还增加了辖区的巡逻力度
Was there anyone suspicious?
有可疑人员吗？
There was a kid who looked quite suspicious.
有一个孩子看着很可疑
He's just a punk who bullies other kids in the area
他就是当地一个小混混 爱欺负别的孩子
and extorts chump change from them.
跟他们要零花钱
We brought him in to question him and checked his alibi too.
我们把他带过来询问 也查过他的不在场证明
The thing is, he always wore a red cap.
可是他总戴着一顶红帽子
Red Cap has been caught.
“红帽子”已经被抓了
I know that, but we all thought he seemed suspicious,
我知道 可是我们都觉得他很可疑
so we questioned him.
就询问了他
I heard the man the lady at the store saw was wearing a red cap.
我听说超市老板娘看到的那个男人 就是戴的红帽子
Witness statements are confidential.
证人的证词是保密的
I'm a regular at the store, so that lady and I are quite close.
我是超市常客 老板娘跟我很熟
She was scared because she saw him,
因为看见那人被吓得不轻
so she asked me to keep an eye out.
所以请我帮忙多留心
I made sure to patrol the area more often.
我就跟她保证以后经常巡逻那一片
I found that cap.
帽子是我捡的
It's true.
真的
Is it common for youngsters your age to use things that others threw out?
你这个年纪的年轻人 会经常捡别人扔的东西用吗？
It was from a designer brand.
那可是设计师品牌
-Can I see it? -I threw it out.
-我能看看吗？ -我扔了
-You did? -Darn it.
-你扔了？ -该死
I had to go to the police station because of it.
就因为它我被带去警局了
I said it wasn't mine, but no one believed me.
我说了不是我的 没人相信我
-How tall are you? -Me?
-你多高？ -我？
I'm 183cm.
我183厘米
Anyway, he was pretty short like a girl.
反正他跟女孩子一样矮矮的
-I can go now, right? -Wait.
-我现在可以走了吧？ -等等
The houses in the area have numbers like this by the entrance.
这一片的房子门口有这种数字
Do you know what this means?
你知道这是什么意思吗？
Isn't it the street address?
不是门牌号吗？
How would I know?
我怎么知道？
This is so annoying.
真烦人
Captain.
班长
About the Uyeong-dong case.
右营洞案
Won Mal-sook's prints were the only thing they found.
他们只找到了元末淑的指纹
FINGERPRINT ANALYSIS REPORT
（指纹分析报告）
WON MAL-SOOK
（元末淑）
What the hell?
怎么回事？
His MO is bothering me.
我觉得他的作案手法有问题
I'm sure it's related to Won Mal-sook's case in Uyeong-dong.
我觉得一定和右营洞元末淑案有关
Hand it over.
给我拿出来
See you again.
再见了
Catching the culprit doesn't mean it's over.
找到凶手不代表就结束了
What? Our job's done the moment we lock them up.
什么？ 把犯人铐起来我们的工作就结束了啊
What more do we have to do?
还要我们怎么样？
We should record everything these criminals said and did
我们要把罪犯说过的做过的 全都记录下来
so we can prevent future crimes and…
这样才能防止将来继续发生犯罪…
Right.
对
You always blow things out of proportion.
你就喜欢夸大事实
No! My goodness.
没有 真是的
Whatever.
随你怎么说
Even the crime records.
还要犯罪记录
You request them for no reason and let them sit on your desk.
无缘无故要那么多记录 把桌子都堆满了
That made everyone from the 31 stations in Seoul
因为这事 我和白科长被全首尔
hurl criticism at me and Superintendent Baek.
31个警察局的人批了个狗血淋头
I'm sure it'll be useful one day.
我敢肯定早晚会有用的
When? How?
什么时候？有什么用？
Gosh, why are you so negative?
天啊 你怎么这么消极？
Come on. It helped us organize
拜托 因为这事我们还整理了
all the files on serious crimes.
所有重大案件的文件呢
It wasn't so bad.
也不算坏事
I guess you're a glass-half-full kind of person.
看来你是那种积极乐观的人
By the way,
对了
detectives feel satisfied when they run around and cuff criminals
刑警能到处亲手捉拿犯人
with their own hands.
才满足啊
That profiler or whatever it's called.
这个侧写师什么的
Are you sure that person is on board?
你确定能找到这种人吗？
Don't worry about that.
别担心了
Just form the team.
尽管组建团队吧
Well…
那个…
That's not something I can decide.
那也不是我能决定的事
-Yes, you can. -Gosh, that's hot.
-是的 你能决定的 -天啊 真烫嘴
Give us this new team.
给我们一个新团队吧
Excuse me. Could you give us more radish kimchi?
老板 能不能再上一份萝卜泡菜？
Goodness.
真可恶
FAMILY VISITATION ROOM
（家属探访室）
I suppose what I told you wasn't useless.
看来我跟你说的话起到作用了
Did something else happen?
又有案子了吗？
What floor?
几楼？
The first floor. But I guess he's targeting other houses too.
一楼 不过我想他也看中其他楼层了
Some of them are on the second floor.
有些是在二楼
I guess he's skilled at picking locks and jumping over walls.
看来他很擅长撬锁和翻墙
Well, home is the safest place.
家是最安全的地方
No one else can see what you do,
别人都看不到你在干什么
except for you and the victim.
除了你和受害者
There were no signs of sexual assault.
没有强奸痕迹
Gosh. He's a pervert that strips victims naked.
天啊 是个喜欢把受害者脱光的变态
Is that not sexual assault?
那不算强奸吗？
And that's why you came to see me.
这就是你来见我的原因
All right. Look.
好了 听着
I got caught because I dragged her to the parking lot.
我被抓是因为我把她拖到了停车场
I got horny, so I did something I don't usually do.
头脑发热 做了平时不常做的事
Oh, boy.
天啊
This is why you should always plan everything and stick to it.
所以说人一定要有计划 还要能坚持
Don't you agree?
你不觉得吗？
Then why did you deviate from your plan?
你那次为什么没按计划来？
Because I was sure I wouldn't get caught.
因为我太自信不会被抓了
Then should I look for ex-cons for robbery and rape in the area first?
那我是不是应该先去找 有强盗和盗窃前科的人？
I guess that's an idea.
我觉得主意不错
You're leaving already?
你这就要走了？
I'm telling you.
我告诉你吧
This guy is sick in the head.
这家伙脑子绝对不正常
He's obsessed with undressing his victims.
他对脱受害者衣服有执念
Detective.
刑警
Will you visit me again?
你还会再来看我吗？
You know…
其实…
I'm an orphan,
我是孤儿
so my commissary account is always empty.
所以我的监狱商店账户里总是没钱
Now that I got a little taste of it…
现在我尝到一点甜头…
I must say, it's very nice.
不得不说 感觉还不错
Oh, boy.
天啊
An orphan?
孤儿？
You went on about how your father…
你刚才不是还说你爸爸…
always scolded you at mealtimes.
总在吃饭时训斥你
Goodness.
天啊
I only call him like that because I have no other option.
我这么叫他是因为没得选
He doesn't deserve to be called a father.
他根本不配被人叫爸爸
He sent his own child to an orphanage.
他把自己的孩子送去孤儿院
That is all I remember…
我就记得这些…
about the man called my father.
那个被叫做我爸爸的男人
DONGBU POLICE STATION
（东部警察局）
That's nuts.
真是疯了
Okay.
知道了
Hey.
喂
Goodness.
真是的
I heard you visited Yang Yong-chul again
我听说你又去找梁龙哲了
and even deposited cash into his commissary account.
还给他的监狱商店账户充了钱
What an embarrassment. I'm humiliated.
真是丢人啊 丢我的人
Criminals understand each other better.
罪犯更能理解罪犯的心理
What?
什么？
Hey, kid. What is he saying?
喂 老幺 他在说什么？
I clearly warned you not to cause trouble.
我明确警告过你不要再找事
Apparently,
现在
Yang Yong-chul is going on about it, all excited.
梁龙哲激动得到处炫耀
That a detective…
说有一个刑警…
That a detective keeps visiting him
有个刑警一直去找他
and asking him for advice!
询问他的意见
The things Yang Yong-chul is saying…
梁龙哲说的…
make sense.
确实有用
You've clearly lost your mind.
你真是疯了
Fine.
行
Criminals understand each other better. So what?
罪犯更能理解罪犯的心理 然后呢？
We need to catch him.
我们要抓住他
-Who? -The real culprit.
-谁？ -真凶
Are you doing this…
你现在这么做
to rebel against me?
是在挑战我吗？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
I caught the culprit and put him behind bars.
我抓住凶手 把他关进监狱了
But you're digging it up again, insisting he's not the real culprit.
现在你把案子翻出来 非说他不是真凶
Talk about being disrespectful.
这种没教养的态度
No, that's not it.
不 不是的
I'm just trying to tell you it's related to this case.
我只是想告诉你它和这个案子有关系
What will you do if Yang Yong-chul
如果梁龙哲开始随口胡诌
starts running his mouth, talking nonsense?
瞎说一气 你该怎么办？
You'll ruin the police's reputation. But that's secondary.
警方的名誉会被你毁掉的 这还是其次
What will you do if the higher-ups hear about it?
万一被上边的人知道了怎么办？
Who will take responsibility for it?
谁来负责？
I will.
我负责
Who do you think you are?
你以为自己是谁啊？
Who do you think you are to take responsibility?
你以为自己是谁 还你负责？
If you were given responsibility because you're such a hotshot,
如果你那么厉害能负这种责任
then why were you sent here?
那怎么会被撵到这里？
If the real culprit is out there,
如果真凶确实逍遥法外
who'll take responsibility for Bang Ki-hoon's life?
邦期勋的人生谁来负责呢？
You little rascal.
你这个混蛋真的是…
Hey, you know what?
喂 不如这样
You should just be the culprit.
你来当凶手吧
You said criminals understand each other.
你不是说罪犯能理解罪犯嘛
You can become a culprit yourself.
那你自己当罪犯好了
I'll arrest you, break your neck, and throw you in prison.
这样我就能逮捕你 把你脖子拧断 扔到监狱去
The culprit for Bang Ki-hoon and Won Mal-sook's cases is the same.
邦期勋案和元末淑案的凶手是同一人
It's his habit of leaving the victim naked.
他的习惯就是把受害者衣服脱光
And he's become even bolder.
而且他现在更大胆了
He won't stop here.
他不会停手的
Were you not listening to anything I said?
我刚才的话 你一句都没听进去 是吗？
I'll catch the culprit.
我一定会抓住凶手
DO NOT ENTER, UNDER INVESTIGATION
（正在调查 禁止进入）
Sexual trauma.
性创伤
Housebreaking.
入室盗窃
History of robbery.
盗窃前科
But he doesn't show up in the system.
可他并没有出现在系统里
The MO is the same, but this one didn't have a sign.
作案手法相同 可这次没有数字标记
Has he become bolder?
他越来越大胆了吗？
Or was this really done by someone else?
还是这次真的是另一个人干的？
LIST OF EX-CONVICTS FOR ROBBERY AND RAPE IN SEOUL
（首尔盗窃和强奸前科犯名单）
I narrowed down the suspects in Won Mal-sook's case.
我把元末淑案的嫌疑人缩小到这些了
What's this?
这里什么？
Ex-convicts who are good at housebreaking.
擅长入室盗窃的前科犯
Do you remember the scratches on the keyhole
你还记得在崔花妍家钥匙孔上
found at Choi Hwa-yeon's place?
发现的划痕吗
-Yes. -It's from opening it by force.
-记得 -那是强行撬锁时留下的
Look. It was found again.
看 这次又发现了
But this is a common technique.
不过这是相同的手法
I'll narrow it down to those who worked as a deliveryman.
我会再缩小到同时做外卖员的人
Deliveryman?
外卖员？
Most of the houses including the one with the theft were marked like this.
包括被盗窃的很多房子都有这种标记
See?
看到了吗？
I'm sure it was him.
我觉得肯定是他
A deliveryman.
一个外卖员
Bang Ki-hoon's case, 214 Daebong-dong.
邦期勋案 大风洞214号
The recent case, 712 Uyeong-dong.
最新的案子 右营洞712号
They aren't too far apart.
这两家离得不远
I'll narrow down the residence using the two areas and find the suspect.
我会利用这两片区域缩小住宅范围 找出嫌疑人
43-1 U-YEONG-DONG
（右营洞43之1号）
Darn it.
真是的
Who is it?
谁啊？
Detective Song Ha-young of Violent Crimes, Dongbu Police Station.
东部警察局刑事科刑警宋霞永
What? I didn't commit any crimes.
什么？我没犯事啊
I just need to confirm your alibi. I will ask--
我只是想和你确认一下不在场证明 我想问…
You randomly come and treat a perfectly innocent guy like me like a criminal,
你就这么随便过来 把我这种无辜良民当罪犯对待
when all I am trying to do is live a good life.
我只想舒舒坦坦过小日子
Goodness, why are you so angry?
天啊 你生那么大气干吗？
-I just need to ask a few… -Darn you.
-我只是想问几个… -该死
Get out. I don't know.
出去 我不知道
Why are the police hassling me?
警察来骚扰我干吗？
I just need to confirm your alibi.
我只是想确认一下你的不在场证明
I said I have no idea.
我说了我不知道
Where were you on the night of the 30th last month?
上个月30号晚上你在哪里？
On Monday, my landlord said
周一 我房东说
the drain was clogged, so I helped her unclog it.
下水道堵了 我去帮她通下水道了
Thank you.
谢谢你
Hello, we're from Dongbu Police Station.
你好 我们是东部警察局的
We would have his prints in the system if the culprit was an ex-convict,
如果凶手是前科犯 我们系统里就会有他的指纹
but it doesn't show up.
可是根本查不到
You expect me to give it to you for the chump change you gave me?
就你给我那点钱还想让我给你出招
Detective, you love freebies a little too much.
刑警 你可真会占小便宜
If you're curious, you must pay the price.
如果你想知道答案 就要付出代价
Nothing is free in this world, is it?
这个世界上没有免费的东西 对吧？
I heard you visited Yang Yong-chul again
我听说你又去找梁龙哲了
and even deposited cash into his commissary account.
还给他的监狱商店账户里存了钱
Don't get cheeky.
别太得意了
I'm not acting cheeky.
我没有得意
Look at me. I ended up in here trying to get some freebies.
看我 就因为占小便宜沦落成这样
Jeez, your words hurt.
天啊 你的话真伤人
Then you should go.
那就走吧
That a detective keeps visiting him
有个刑警一直去找他
and asking him for advice!
询问他的意见
Yang Yong-chul.
梁龙哲
That's enough.
够了
All I did was give an answer to your question.
我只是回答你的问题而已
Only someone like me would do that.
也就我愿意这么做
If it had been other punks, they would never say a word.
换成别的混蛋 一个字都不会跟你说
It'll expose all their methods. They'd be insane to answer you.
这会暴露他们的手法 他们疯了才会告诉你
Jeez, all right.
真是的 行了
You must've grown on me in that short while. What's with me?
这么短的时间就被你打动了 我这是怎么了？
Family Visitation Room.
家属探访室
I keep getting soft because I see you in a place like…
我会心软是因为在这种地方见你…
Gosh, you're so hasty.
真是的 你别急啊
This is my final warning. Don't step over the line.
我最后一次警告你 不要太过分
You really don't know how I feel, do you?
你真的不明白我的感受 对吗？
This is for sure.
说真的
Once he gets a taste of this,
一旦他尝到那种味道
he'll never be able to quit.
就再也戒不掉了
If you don't catch him…
如果你们不抓到他
It'll happen again.
凶案还会继续发生
ERADICATE PETTY THUGS THAT EAT AWAY OUR ECONOMY
（铲除阻碍平民经济的社区流氓）
You little punk! How dare you do this?
你这小混蛋 你怎么敢做那种事？
You broke into my home in broad daylight!
光天化日闯进我们家
Darn it.
该死
So when your girlfriend was asleep,
所以当时你女朋友正在睡觉
you caught him trying to break in, right?
他准备进来时被你当场抓住 对吗？
-Yes. -Okay, I understand.
-是啊 -好 我了解了
This isn't the place to talk.
这里不适合说话
-There's a room for interrogation-- -No, I said this guy
-那边有一个房间专门用来审… -不是 我说这家伙
had a knife in his pocket!
口袋里还装了把刀
-What? -If I hadn't shown up then,
-什么？ -要是我那会儿没出现
my Young-sook and my unborn child would've died in his hands!
我的荣淑和肚子里的孩子 就要死在他手里了
Hey, this is attempted murder!
喂 这可是谋杀未遂
-Darn it. -Excuse me, sir.
-该死 -先生
Please don't shout. Calm down.
请不要大声喧哗 冷静点
Well, hey.
喂
That thing in your pocket. Pull it out.
你口袋里装的东西 拿出来
Pull it out.
拿出来
I'm sorry.
对不起
-You jerk! -Sir.
-你这个混蛋 -先生
Calm down, sir. That's public property.
冷静点 先生 这是公共财产
I can't see it, so lift it up.
我看不到 举高点
Higher.
再高点
Scissors? Why do you carry that around?
剪刀？你带这个干吗？
I'm really sorry.
我真的错了
-What's the charge? -Housebreaking.
-什么罪名？ -入室盗窃
It's attempted murder! He has a weapon!
是谋杀未遂啊 他有武器
Yes, sir, we get it. So please stop shouting.
好的 先生 我们知道了 请不要大声喧哗
Your child will get scared.
会吓着肚子里的孩子的
Hey.
喂
Take it as evidence.
当证据收起来
Okay.
好
Grab a seat, please.
请坐
Put it in.
放进去
Hurry up and put it in.
快点放进去
-Name. -Cho Kang-moo.
-姓名 -赵江武
-Age. -Eighteen years old.
-年龄 -18岁
Give me your ID.
把你的身份证给我
I don't have one. My birthday hasn't passed.
我没有身份证 还没过生日
Gosh, you're still wet behind the ears.
天啊 还这么小就不干正事
How did you get in?
怎么进去的？
I just picked it open.
我就是撬开的
The details!
说清楚点
I used those scissors.
我用剪刀
You should be studying instead of doing that.
你现在应该去上学啊 不应该干这个
Who taught you to pick doors by using scissors?
谁教你用剪刀撬锁的？
I just learned it from friends.
就是跟朋友们学的
You have some wonderful friends.
你交的可真是好朋友
What's with your hair?
你头发怎么了？
Sorry?
什么？
Weren't you wearing a cap?
你是不是经常戴帽子？
You have helmet hair.
头发被压出印子了
Oh, yes.
是
Where's your cap?
你的帽子呢？
-Sorry? -Where's the cap you wore?
-什么？ -你戴的帽子呢？
I lost it on the way here.
在路上不小心丢了
You're so clumsy.
你怎么这么不小心
Get up for a second.
站起来一下
-How tall are you? -I'm 167cm.
-你多高？ -我167厘米
Kids who say they're 167cm are always 165cm.
说自己167的孩子一般也就165
No, I'm 167cm tall.
不 我就是167
Then let's compare. I'm 175cm.
那我们来比比看啊 我175
Let's compare.
来比比个子
Those who say that are barely over 170cm.
说自己175的一般只有170多点
No, you jerk. I'm 175cm.
说什么啊 混蛋 我就是175
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Is this a blind date?
相亲吗？
Sit down.
坐下
As for his height…
他的身高…
I'm not sure.
我不确定
Anyway, he was pretty short like a girl.
反正他跟女孩子一样矮矮的
His fingerprint identification will come out tomorrow, right?
他的指纹识别结果 明天就出来了 对吧？
Sorry?
什么？
The scissor. You just took it in as evidence.
那把剪刀 你刚拿去做证据了
-It's not-- -It should come out tomorrow.
-那个不是… -明天结果就出来了
Fingerprint analysis.
指纹分析
Right?
对吧？
Yes.
对
It'll come out tomorrow.
明天就出来了
What's your address?
你的地址？
Your address! You little…
问你地址呢 你这个小…
Write down why and how you broke into that house in detail.
把你强行进入那个房子的原因 和方法详细写下来
I just thought…
我只是以为…
no one was inside, so I went in.
屋里没人 才进去的
Write it down. And don't speak unless spoken to.
写下来 还有我没问你就别说话
-Write as many details as you can. -Okay.
-写得越详细越好 -好的
Hey, when we were working on Bang Ki-hoon's case…
喂 我们调查邦期勋案的时候…
Yes?
怎么了？
We had a statement from a witness about Red Cap.
有一个证人提到过红帽子
-Did she say the guy was short? -Yes.
-她是不是说那个人个子矮矮的？ -是
But I doubt that it's him. He's still wet behind his ears.
可是我觉得不像是这小子 他还是个小屁孩呢
Can you ask the victim
请问一下受害者
if he was wearing a cap before he was brought in?
这孩子被带来前有没有戴帽子？
And check if there were any caps thrown out on the way here.
还有检查一下来的路边 有没有被扔掉的帽子
Go.
去吧
Okay.
好
Hold on. Not yet.
等等 先别急
This is Dongbu Police Station.
这里是东部警察局
I'm going to register an item under evidence.
我要在证据里额外登记一件物品
Run a fingerprint test on it.
把上边的指纹测试一下
It's urgent.
急着用
Put a rush on it.
请尽快
What you just did is a serious crime.
你刚才的行为是重罪
You were caught red-handed picking the door with scissors.
你用剪刀撬锁时被当场抓获
That could have been a murder weapon.
那个可能被当作谋杀凶器
They were just scissors.
只是剪刀而已
You can kill people with scissors because you can stab them.
剪刀也能杀死人 因为可以捅人
How can you stab someone with scissors? That's horrible.
怎么能用剪刀捅人呢？太可怕了
-You think it's horrible? -Yes.
-你觉得很可怕？ -是的
Which part is horrible?
哪个方面可怕？
Stabbing someone or killing someone?
捅人可怕还是杀人可怕？
It's both, of course.
当然都可怕
How many times have you broken in before?
你入室盗窃过多少次？
This is my first time, of course.
这是第一次
You can climb walls too, right?
你还会翻墙 对吧？
Thieves these days can easily climb up three floors.
现在的小偷翻个三层楼都轻轻松松
Is it because you're young? You guys are so full of energy.
是因为年纪小吗？ 你们这些孩子精力这么旺盛
It's easy with the pipes.
只要有管道就好办了
You can climb pipes too?
你还会爬管道？
Which floor did you break into before?
你之前撬过几楼的房子？
I know it wasn't your first time.
我知道这不是你第一次
Even if you're a petty thief, if you don't come clean now,
就算你只是个小偷 如果现在不坦白
you'll end up with a heavier sentence.
最后也要判重罪
So just come clean when you have a chance.
所以趁你还有机会尽快坦白
That's better for you.
这也是为你好
It was on the first floor.
是一楼
What about the second floor?
那二楼呢？
Do you remember which house it was?
你还记得是哪家吗？
You have to tell the truth to get a lenient sentence.
坦白真相才能从宽处理
It was just an ordinary house.
那就是个普通人家
I guess no one was home since you didn't get caught.
你没有被抓 看来是没人在家
Yes. I don't break into houses unless they are empty.
是 我只挑屋里没人的房子撬锁
What if someone was there when you broke in?
万一你进去的时候屋里有人呢？
Then I would come out or hide.
那我就赶快出去或者藏起来
You've never been caught other than today?
除了今天你从没被抓住过？
No.
没有
Write everything down there. All the houses you've broken into so far.
全都写下来 迄今为止你撬锁进去的所有房子
I'm going to.
我就准备写呢
But I'm getting confused because you keep talking to me.
不过你一直跟我说话 我都记不清了
What the…
什么…
SUSPECT INFORMATION
（嫌犯个人信息）
GRANDMOTHER: PARK HYUN-JA
（祖母：朴晛嬨）
How long have you lived with your grandmother?
你和奶奶在一起生活多久了？
Did you talk to my grandmother?
你跟我奶奶说了？
You're a minor.
你是未成年
It's our duty to call your guardian.
我们有义务通知你的监护人
Right.
是
How long have you lived with your grandmother?
你和奶奶在一起生活多久了？
Ever since I was ten.
从十岁就在一起住了
-What about your parents? -I don't talk to them.
-你的父母呢？ -没有联系
-Both of them? -Yes.
-都没有联系了吗？ -是
-Did they get a divorce? -I'm not sure.
-他们离婚了吗？ -我不知道
My mom ran away, and my dad abandoned us.
我妈妈跑了 我爸爸离家出走了
Is my grandmother here?
我奶奶来了吗？
Why?
怎么了？
You don't want to worry her?
怕她担心？
Fuck.
该死
INTERROGATION ROOM
（审讯室）
He didn't lose it.
他没扔帽子
He put it behind a telephone pole.
他把帽子藏在电线杆后边
-Isn't this expensive? -What?
-这很贵吧？ -什么？
Look at this brand.
看这个牌子
Right. It's pretty expensive.
对 这个很贵
By the way, did you get anything from him?
对了 你从他嘴里问出什么了吗？
He can't be the culprit for Bang Ki-hoon's…
他不会是邦期勋案的凶手…
Can you run a fingerprint test on the scissors he brought in?
你可以给他带来的剪刀 做个指纹测试吗？
Captain Park already requested it to be expedited.
朴班长已经申请加急做了
I see.
知道了
Let me borrow that.
我借用一下这个
-If it's not urgent, let me use it. -What?
-不急着用的话 先让我用一下 -什么？
I just need it for a while.
我只用一会儿
Is this your cap?
这是你的帽子吗？
It's yours, right?
是你的吧？
It's expensive. Don't lose it.
很贵 别弄丢了
Thank you.
谢谢你
-You must like caps. -Yes.
-你肯定很喜欢帽子 -是的
Write a new one, and number the houses you robbed.
另起一行写下一个 你偷过的房子的门牌号
The one you just wrote is number one.
你刚写的是第一个
The next one is number two.
接下来写第二个
DAEBONG-DONG 14-1
（大风洞14之1号）
Then you must have a lot of expensive caps.
看来你有很多很贵的帽子
I only have one. This is really expensive.
我只有这一顶 太贵了
It's just you and your grandma. You must need a bigger allowance.
就你和奶奶 零花钱肯定不够买帽子
I don't get an allowance.
我没有零花钱
I earn my own money.
我自己挣钱买的
-You must have a part-time job. -Yes.
-你肯定有兼职 -是的
But you still robbed houses?
这样还要入室盗窃？
I guess you needed more money.
看来你花销很大
I was bored.
我太无聊了
-You were bored? -Yes.
-太无聊？ -是的
I just did it a few times for fun.
我只是图好玩偷了几次
Kids around my age steal other people's stuff.
你不知道青春期的孩子都会这样吗？
You've never done that?
你从没偷过吗？
I'll never do it again.
我再也不会这么做了
I'll promise that I'll never steal again, so can I go home?
我发誓我不会再偷东西了 我可以回家了吗？
I'll promise I'll never do it again. Can't you just send me home?
我发誓我不会再做了 你让我回家不行吗？
I can't.
不行
I told you earlier.
我跟你说过了
-This could have been attempted murder. -How…
-这也许会变成谋杀未遂 -怎么会…
How is this attempted murder?
怎么会是谋杀未遂呢？
I was just trying to steal some money.
我只是想偷点钱而已
Besides, I couldn't even steal anything because I got caught.
而且我还没动手就被抓住了
When you break in with a weapon, it's not a simple theft charge.
持械入室就不是简单的盗窃罪了
It's special larceny.
是特殊盗窃罪
It's a serious criminal offense that can put you away for ten years.
这种刑事重罪足够判你十年监禁
And also…
而且…
it wasn't your first time.
你不是初犯
We need to know how much money you stole and what you did with what you stole.
我们得调查你偷过多少钱 拿赃款做了什么
So write down when, where, how you broke in, how much you stole,
所以把你入室盗窃的时间 地点、手法和金额统统写下来
and every single thing you stole.
包括每一件赃物
I mean…
不是…
Isn't robbing empty houses better than extorting money from other kids?
偷空房子应该 比抢其他孩子零花钱好吧？
Is that what you think?
你是这么想的吗？
My neighborhood is full of those kids. But you don't interrogate them like this.
我们那片全是那种孩子 可你们从不审问他们
Is that how your grandmother will think too?
你奶奶也这样想吗？
Write them down.
都写下来 快点
What part-time job do kids your age have?
你这个年纪的孩子能做什么兼职？
Damn it.
该死
Do you want me to write it or not?
你到底想不想让我写了？
Can I just plead the Fifth?
我可以行使沉默权吗？
Your questions are annoying me.
你的问题打扰到我了
Okay, you're free to do so.
好 你可以行使这个权利
But it could work to your disadvantage.
不过可能对你不利
If our investigation reveals that you're guilty of everything,
如果我们调查发现你所有罪名都成立
you may be subject to a heavier punishment.
你可能面临更重的惩罚
I've worked as a delivery boy.
我兼职做外卖员
We questioned all the delivery guys who work in the area
我们询问了当地所有外卖员
but couldn't track him down.
可是没查出他来
And as a server.
还有服务员
Write down the numbers I say.
把我念的数字都写下来
-Damn it. -Two.
-该死 -二
What are these numbers?
这些数字是什么？
I'm sure you know what they are.
我觉得你应该知道是什么
The number 2 at 214 Daebong-dong means a woman lives there alone.
大风洞214号门口的数字二 指的是屋里住着独居女性
What is this?
这到底是什么？
Two means an adult female.
二指的是成年女性
Three means a kid.
三指的是儿童
And the number one means…
而数字一指的是…
an adult male.
成年男性
What's wrong? Are you anxious?
怎么了？你很紧张吗？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
You were too meticulous
对于一个只是为了好玩
for someone who robbed houses a few times "for fun."
入室盗窃几次的人来说 你太严谨了
You know them, don't you?
你认识她们 对吧？
No, I don't.
不 不认识
We found a fingerprint at the scene.
我们在现场发现了一个指纹
Why do you keep telling me this?
你为什么一直跟我说这个？
We'll get the results that prove it matches yours tomorrow.
我们明天就能拿到结果 证明你的指纹跟它相符合了
Kang-moo.
江武
Why did you undress them?
你为什么要脱她们的衣服？
It's what that scumbag did all the time.
因为那个混蛋就总做这种事
"That scumbag"?
“那个混蛋”？
My dad.
我爸爸
-Come here. -Please save me. I'm sorry.
-给我过来 -放过我吧 我错了
Darn it.
该死的
-I'm sorry. -Get up.
-我错了 -给我起来
Please forgive me.
请放了我吧
-Darn it. -I'm sorry.
-该死 -我错了
Every time I saw her just putting up with it, it made me so angry.
每次看到她忍气吞声我都特别生气
SERIAL RAPIST RED CAP'S WHEREABOUTS STILL REMAIN UNKNOWN
（连环强奸犯“红帽子”下落不明）
Damn it.
该死
When did you get here?
你什么时候来的？
-You forgot to take an umbrella, right? -How did you know?
-你忘记带伞了吧？ -你怎么知道？
The floor was wet, so I wiped it.
地板都湿了 我刚擦过了
It's just a food stall. Can't you just hang out with me today?
区区一个小吃摊而已 你今天陪陪我不行吗？
Look at you belittling me again.
你又在小看我
Ki-hoon!
期勋
Seriously.
真是的
It's raining.
还在下雨啊
Are you sure you found it?
你们真的找到了吗？
My fingerprint.
我的指纹
You lied to me, didn't you?
你骗了我 是吗？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
I wiped everything I touched.
我把痕迹都擦干净了
Which house did you find it in?
你们在哪个房子里找到的？
There is no such thing as a perfect crime.
没有完美犯罪
And you'll find out tomorrow whether or not I lied to you.
明天你就知道我有没有骗你了
He confessed.
他都招了
You little…
你这个小…
COURT ORDER
（法院传令）
Your retrial request has been denied.
你的重申请求已被驳回
We got the results back.
我们拿到结果了
The unidentified fingerprint
查不到身份的指纹
does belong to Cho Kang-moo.
就是赵江武的
It wasn't in the system because he's a minor.
因为他未成年所以没有录入系统
FINGERPRINT ANALYSIS REPORT
（指纹分析报告）
99.99 PERCENT MATCH
（99.99%符合）
This is the first news this morning.
今晨第一则新闻
A teen boy pretended to be Red Cap
为了迷惑警方 一名青少年
to confuse the police and committed murders.
假装成“红帽子” 并实施谋杀
The brutal details of his crimes have now been revealed.
他所犯罪行的残忍细节被公开
The suspect, Cho, used his image as a diligent young man
嫌犯赵某营造出勤奋年轻人的形象
-to go about his daily life -Hello?
-在白天正常生活 -喂？
and escaped the police dragnet as if nothing had happened
逃过警方的彻底搜查 即使谋杀完两名独居女性
even after murdering two women who lived alone.
依然能假装若无其事
Cho is an 18-year-old minor.
赵某是18岁的未成年人
He does not have a resident registration number yet,
尚未登记居民身份信息
so his fingerprints weren't registered in the system,
因此指纹并未录入系统
which he used to his advantage.
他借此钻了空子
Why did you undress the victims?
你为什么要脱受害者的衣服？
What will happen to Bang Ki-hoon, who's in jail now?
现在在坐牢的邦期勋会怎么样？
-Why did you kill them? -Did you kill anyone else?
-你为什么要杀人？ -你还杀别人了吗？
-How many people did you kill? -Did you copy Red Cap?
-你杀了多少人？ -你是在模仿“红帽子”吗？
-Say something! -Just a comment!
-说几句吧
-Bring her back you evil jerk! -Get out of the way, please.
-把她还给我 你这个混蛋 -别挡路
-You jerk! -Bring her back!
-你这个混蛋 -把她还给我
Bring her back to life!
把她还给我
-Let me in! -Stop it!
-让我进去 -快停下
Let me in just once!
让我进去 就一次
Settle down.
请安静
Bring her back to life!
把她还给我
You attacked the victim who was in her room.
受害者在卧室时被你袭击
Then you strangled her.
然后你掐住她的脖子
You got on top of her.
你骑在她身上
And then you took her top off. Is that right?
然后把她上衣脱了 对吗？
Right. You took her top off.
对 你把她上衣脱了
TWISTED DESIRES OF A TEENAGE BOY
（一个青少年的变态欲望）
CHO TARGETED WOMEN LIVING ALONE AND COMMITTED MURDER TWICE
（赵某盯上独居女性犯下两起命案）
The victim's home was robbed of 290 million won.
受害者家中被盗2.9亿韩元
Afraid of retaliation…
因担心被报复…
Everyone is so interested in crime cases.
现在大家对罪案都这么关注
Yet why is it so hard to catch criminals?
可抓罪犯怎么还这么难
Anyway, good work.
算了 你做得不错
It's a relief that we ended up catching him.
终于抓到他也算松了一口气
If we didn't, there may have been a third victim.
如果没抓到 可能还会有第三个受害者
Do you think so?
你这么觉得吗？
I feel bad for the victims to say this,
虽然这么说有点对不住受害者
but for a guy who committed the same murder twice,
可对于已经杀了两个人的人来说
committing another one would be nothing for him.
再杀一个根本不算什么
You're right.
你说得对
He's still a kid.
他还是个孩子
Cho Kang-moo…
赵江武…
already showed boldness in his second crime.
但是第二次杀人就已经很胆大了
He saw her house key on her
他看到那女生身上挂着家里钥匙
and suspected she lived alone.
就猜测她是独居
He erased his traces with the toilet paper from the bathroom.
还用卫生间厕纸擦掉了他的所有痕迹
When I checked again,
我检查现场时
both victims' homes only had the core of toilet paper rolls left behind.
两名受害者家里都只剩厕纸芯了
Why was I so stupid to not notice that?
我怎么没注意到呢？
You can't be perfect. We're human too.
你也不能面面俱到啊 我们都是凡人
It's our job to find as many clues as we can.
我们的工作是尽量多找到线索
Which is why I'm saying
所以我才建议
we need to do research on criminal behavior analysis.
我们要研究犯罪行为分析
We have to find that out.
我们要把那些找出来
Also, it's not as if these guys stop because they go to jail.
还有把那些家伙送进监狱后 他们也不会停手的
They don't.
不会的
It's important to catch them.
抓住他们很重要
But we have to be prepared for when they go back into society.
但是我们还要做好准备 应对他们返回社会的时候
If we do research and make data out of these similar criminal cases,
如果我们好好研究 从这些相似案例中总结出数据
I'm certain it will come in handy.
我敢肯定一定有用
Just like how you went to see Yang Yong-chul to catch Cho Kang-moo.
就像你为了抓住赵江武去找梁龙哲
How are things with Captain Park?
朴班长那边怎么样？
It was Captain Park who got a confession out of Bang Ki-hoon.
是朴班长让邦期勋认罪的
Nothing will change.
没什么变化
That's a relief then.
那就好
I'll give you a ride.
我载你一程吧
No, it's fine. I want to walk a bit. Go home.
没事 我想走走 回去吧
-Get home safely. -I will.
-路上注意安全 -我会的
I only call him like that because I have no other option.
我这么叫他是因为没得选
He doesn't deserve to be called a father.
他根本不配被人叫爸爸
He sent his own child to an orphanage.
他把自己的孩子送去孤儿院
-It's what that scumbag did all the time. -"That scumbag"?
-因为那个混蛋就总做这种事 -“那个混蛋”？
My dad.
我爸爸
Cho Kang-moo's unusual behavior stemmed from his resentment and hatred
赵江武出于对父母的怨愤和仇恨
toward his parents.
才有了不正常的行为
He feels absolutely no remorse for the murders he committed.
他对自己犯下的命案毫无悔恨之心
Which is why I'm saying
所以我才建议
we need to do research on criminal behavior analysis.
我们要研究犯罪行为分析
We have to find that out.
我们要把那些找出来
Is there anything you would like to say to the victim's family?
你有什么想对受害者遗属说的吗？
Look here!
看这里
How do you feel right now?
你现在什么感受？
Do you have anything to say?
你有什么想说的吗？
Hello. I'm reporter Im Moo-sik from Daehan Daily.
你好 我是《大韩日报》记者林武植
DAEHAN DAILY
（《大韩日报》）
FALSELY ACCUSED BANG POLICE SUSPECTED OF COERCION
（方某被诬告 警方涉嫌逼供）
Over here!
这边
I'm currently in front of Dongbu Police Station
我现在就站在深陷逼供风波的
which is currently under suspicion of coercion.
东部警察局门前
People are demanding the truth
警方对方某屈打成招
and an apology to Bang from the police
人们要求警方还方某清白
who beat him to get a false confession.
并道歉
The people also strongly condemned
人们还强烈谴责
the police for using coercion in their investigations
警方在调查时逼供
which was revealed…
此事一经曝光…
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY COMMISSIONER GENERAL LEE JIN-CHUL
（首尔地方警察厅 李镇哲厅长）
Darn it!
该死
-How would I know when I didn't do it? -That's not it.
-我没做的事情我怎么知道？ -不是那样的
-Just hold on for now. -No.
-稍等一下 -不是的
-I told you not to call. -He's not here.
-我跟你说了别打了 -他不在
-I already told you. -No.
-我跟你说过了 -不是的
Don't call us.
别给我打电话了
No, he's not here.
不 他不在
-How many times did I tell you? -He's not here.
-我跟你们说多少遍了？ -他不在
I already told you.
我跟你们说过了
We demand a resignation!
我们要求他辞职
-Resign!
-辞职
Does Detective Song Ha-young work here?
宋霞永刑警是在这里工作吗？
He's not here.
他不在
What brings you here?
有什么事吗？
-Who is he? -He's from Daehan Daily.
-他是谁？ -他是《大韩日报》的
I'm Reporter Im Moo-sik from Daehan Daily.
我是《大韩日报》的林武植记者
DAEHAN DAILY IM MOO-SIK
（《大韩日报》林武植）
It's still an ongoing investigation.
那起案件还在调查中
We'll hold a press pool when it's time.
等时机合适我们会举行媒体发布会
You're Captain Park who investigated Bang Ki-hoon's case, right?
你是调查邦期勋案的朴班长吧？
I have no comments. Please leave.
无可奉告 请走吧
Please leave.
请走吧
I came to see Detective Song Ha-young.
我是来找宋霞永刑警的
I heard he got help from Yang Yong-chul,
我听说这次能将赵江武捉拿归案
also known as Red Cap, who's in prison for Cho Kang-moo's case.
是多亏了在押犯 “红帽子”梁龙哲的帮助
Is that true?
是真的吗？
Nothing like that happened.
根本没那回事
I just got back from meeting Yang Yong-chul.
我刚去见了梁龙哲
Darn it.
可恶
Do you believe what that piece of trash said? Please leave.
那种人渣的话你也信吗？赶紧走吧
-Leave. -Hold on.
-走吧 -等等
DAEHAN DAILY IM MOO-SIK
（《大韩日报》林武植）
Follow me.
跟我来
People are furious a detective falsely charged an innocent man
一名警察诬告无辜之人 还有警察
and asked for help from an imprisoned criminal
为抓住凶手向关押犯人寻求帮助
to catch the culprit due to their incompetence.
民众对种种无能行为感到无比愤怒
On top of that, it's been reported Inspector Song
除此之外 据报道
from Seoul's Dongbu Police Station
东部警察局的宋刑警
visited Yang Yong-chul, also known as Red Cap,
探访梁龙哲 即“红帽子”
the culprit behind the serial rape cases.
连环强奸案后的凶手
People were shocked to learn Song received help from him
了解到宋某为了破案向他寻求帮助后
in order to solve this case.
民众无比震惊
It's been revealed
据称
Assistant Inspector Song from Violent Crimes
重案组的宋刑警
visited the imprisoned Yang Yong-chul
探访关押的梁龙哲
and even gave him money to receive advice regarding the crime.
甚至用金钱和他交换破案建议
People are demanding an investigation
民众要求调查
on why the police ended up giving up their dignity.
警方为何做出这种放弃尊严的事情
Hey.
喂
Are you all right?
你还好吗？
Yes, of course.
是 还好
I don't think this is going to die down easily.
我觉得这个风波不会那么快消散的
That's why I--
所以我…
It's not as if a lot of people liked me after all.
反正以前也有很多人不喜欢我
The number of them simply went up a little more.
只是现在这个数字变大了而已
Gosh, what are you saying?
天啊 你这说的什么话？
I'm really fine.
我真的没事
It's the victims and their families
我们真正应该关心的
who we should really worry about.
是受害者和他们的家属
I would do the same thing
如果再遇到同样的情况
if we came across the same situation again.
我还会那样做的
I don't regret it.
我不后悔
POLICE OFFICER PERSONNEL RECORD
（警察人事档案）
TURNS OUT A PRISONER SOLVED THE CASE, NOT THE POLICE
（破案人原来是罪犯 不是警察）
I'm back.
我回来了
-You're home. -Yes.
-你回来了 -是
-Did you eat? -I already ate.
-吃过了吗？ -吃过了
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
Ha-young was the one who caught the real culprit, not Yang Yong-chul.
抓住真凶的是宋霞永 不是梁龙哲
If it weren't for him,
如果不是他
that poor man would've served his sentence.
就要害另一个人坐牢了
That's what you think.
那是你的想法
The FBI has been using the method of interviewing culprits
美国联邦调查局过去二十年 都在使用这种采访犯人的办法
for the last 20 years as a part of their investigation.
已经是他们调查的一部分了
It's nothing wrong.
这不是什么错事
Rather, no one taught him, but he thought of that alone.
而且没人教过他 是他自己想出来的
I get it. But the thing is,
我理解 可是
no one knows that out there.
别人不理解啊
If they don't know, we must let them know.
如果他们不懂 我们就得帮他们理解
This is the perfect time to form the Behavioral Analysis Team.
现在是组建行动分析小组的完美时机
Young-soo, please learn to read the room, will you?
荣秀 有点眼力见 行吗？
We're about to get dragged to the commissioner's office.
我们都要被拉到厅长办公室了
That's great. Go ask him to form that team.
正好 去问问他组建团队的事
Darn you. Good grief.
哎哟 天啊
Please trust me this once.
这次请相信我
It's the old man.
是老大
-The commissioner? -Yes.
-厅长吗？ -是
You go ask him to form you that team.
你去让他给你组建团队吧
-Let's go.
-走吧
-Darn it. -You got this.
-真是的 -你等着
-We'll be back. -Okay.
-我们一会儿回来 -好
Not only did the police accuse an innocent man as the culprit,
警方不仅将无辜市民指控为凶手
but they also arrested Cho, an 18-year-old…
还逮捕了一名18岁名为赵某的…
What will you do about the public opinion?
你们想怎么处理现在的舆论？
If the Special Crime Squad
如果让机搜队
had taken the case and put an end to it,
处理这个案子 让他们结案
this wouldn't have happened.
根本不会发生这种事
It wouldn't be good manners
东部警察局抓的人
for us to work on a culprit caught by the Dongbu Police Station.
让我们管恐怕不合规矩
They're already going crazy
你们把一个无辜市民
about how you locked up an innocent man for a year.
关了一年已经让民众气愤至极了
Can we let them ridicule us saying a convict caught the criminal?
还要让他们嘲笑说 服刑犯抓住了罪犯吗？
I've had enough of this incompetence.
我受够你们的无能了
Who leaked the fact that he's Red Cap?
谁把他是“红帽子”的消息 传出去的？
It's not that someone leaked the information.
不是有人泄露了消息
That jerk is putting on a show to grab people's attention.
是那个混蛋故意显摆引人关注
What have you done right as detectives?
你们顶着警察的头衔做过正事吗？
-We'll do better. -We're sorry.
-我们会努力的 -我们错了
Everyone at Dongbu Police Station will be disciplined!
东部警察局所有人都要受罚
Simply disciplining them won't solve anything.
光罚他们解决不了任何问题
What are you going to do about this?
你们能有什么办法？
I'm sorry.
我错了
-Darn it. -Tell him.
-真是的 -告诉他吧
Sorry?
什么？
-Tell him what? -That thing.
-告诉他什么？ -那件事
-That thing? -Pilot thing.
-那件事？ -飞行师的事
What are you two doing?
你们两个在干什么？
I'm sorry. He just whispered to me.
抱歉 他在跟我说悄悄话
-I didn't get that. I'm sorry. -That pilot thing.
-我没听清 不好意思 -飞行师那事
Commissioner.
厅长
-There might be a way. -Yes.
-也许有办法 -是的
What is it?
什么办法？
I'll give you some more.
我再给你点
-Thank you. -Sure.
-谢谢你 -没事
Enjoy.
请慢用
Hello.
你好
One ramyeon, please.
请来一份泡面
-How much is it? -Just go.
-多少钱？ -你走吧
I don't take money from a friend.
我不要朋友的钱
Thank you for finding…
谢谢你找到…
the real culprit.
真凶
You were always like that.
你以前也总是这样
You pretended like you didn't care about people,
假装不关心别人
but you always did behind their backs.
实际一直在背后默默关心
We'd like to pay the tab.
我们这桌结账
Sure. It's 8,000 won.
好 八千韩元
Thank you for finding the real culprit.
谢谢你找到真凶
If you're my friend, take it.
当我是朋友的话就收下吧
You rascal. Why didn't you come out sooner?
你小子 不早点出来干吗呢？
You weren't on a stakeout, were you?
你不是在监视我吧？
Did you read the book I gave you last time?
我上次给你的书你看了吗？
I think we can finally form the Behavioral Analysis Team
我们终于能组建出行动分析小组了
as long as you agree.
只要你同意加入
Sorry?
什么？
Do you remember what I said about profilers?
你还记得我怎么说的侧写师吗？
If you hadn't caught Cho Kang-moo,
如果你没有抓住赵江武
he would've continued to murder people.
他也许会继续杀人
We can stop that from happening.
我们可以阻止这种事
We pretty much stopped Cho Kang-moo too.
赵江武就是我们阻止的
-Can you explain in simple terms? -Okay.
-你可以用简单的话解释一下吗？ -好
You can officially go around interviewing inmates.
你可以正式去采访犯人了
How is that possible?
怎么会这样？
You said it was helpful to visit Yang Yong-chul.
你说过找梁龙哲有用
We can just say it was the duty of the Behavioral Analysis Team
我们就说采访梁龙哲是
to go interview Yang Yong-chul.
行动分析小组的职责
Those above will have an excuse to calm the people down.
上边的人有理由平息民众怒火了
And for me, I'm thrilled because I can finally do some real work.
而我 我太激动了 终于能做大事了
It'll definitely help in solving similar cases.
这个肯定对解决相似案件很有帮助
Honestly, this team should've been formed long ago.
其实早就应该组建这个团队了
But I don't exactly know…
可是我不太明白…
what a profiler does.
侧写师究竟是做什么的
It's all right. Just do as you've done.
没事的 你就像以前一样
Others couldn't understand,
其他人不理解
but you instinctively knew that this was necessary.
可是你本能觉得应该那样做
That's why you continued to visit Yang Yong-chul.
所以你才会继续去找梁龙哲
And as for studying,
至于该学习的东西
you and I can start doing that now.
你现在就可以开始跟我学了
I believe this was something
我相信这件事
someone had to do someday.
早晚要有人做
And I'm certain…
而且我觉得
that you're the perfect person for this job.
你就是这个工作的最佳人选
DONGBU POLICE STATION, VIOLENT CRIMES ASSISTANT INSPECTOR SONG HA-YOUNG
（东部警察局重案组警察 宋霞永）
MINDHUNTER
（《心灵猎人》）
ERADICATE PETTY THUGS THAT EAT AWAY OUR ECONOMY
（铲除阻碍平民经济的社区流氓）
Five, four, three, two, one!
五、四、三、二、一
The new millennium was welcomed with vigor in the Jongno area,
钟路区到处是喜迎千禧年的欢乐气氛
and twice as many people compared to last year have gathered.
这里的聚集人数是去年的两倍
Around 500,000 people flocked to Yeouido, Seoul,
约五十万人涌入首尔汝矣岛
where the Cherry Blossom Festival took place.
这里正在举行樱花节 感受春的美景
People enjoyed the spring breeze with family and lovers
人们与家人或恋人同游 沉浸在春日微风
as they walked along the Han River amid fluttering petals.
漫步在汉江边摇曳的花丛中
-Mom! Dad! -You'll trip. Be careful.
-妈妈 爸爸 -小心摔跤 慢点跑
Hey, kid.
喂 小朋友
Do you want me to buy you ice cream?
你想不想让我给你买冰激凌吃？
Did you pick one?
你选好了吗？
This one.
要这个
TAEHO'S CORNER SHOP
（太虎家小店）
Is it good?
好吃吗？
I have more ice cream at home.
我家里还有好多冰激凌
Do you want to get some more?
你想不想去吃？
Come on. Let's go.
来 跟我走吧
MINDHUNTER
（《心灵猎人》）
I'll start the briefing.
现在我开始讲解
Parts of the victim's body were found in the alleyway.
在小巷里发现了受害者部分身体
A five-year-old girl, Lee Soo-hyun, was reported missing,
我们收到五岁女孩李秀贤失踪的报案
so we're looking into it now.
所以我们正在调查
"Criminal behavioral analyst"? Do you run psychological tests?
“犯罪行为分析师”？ 你要做心理测试吗？
We study the minds of criminals.
我们研究罪犯的心理
We came to help out with the investigation.
我们是来协助调查的
A profiler is a psychologist-like police officer,
侧写师是心理学家式的警察
not a police officer-like psychologist.
不是警察式的心理学家
A profiler must detect what happened at the crime scene.
侧写师必须查明案发现场发生的一切
-Why was it her? -Where is the culprit hiding?
-为什么选她？ -凶手藏在哪里？
What kind of trait does the culprit have?
凶手有什么特征？
Who is the culprit?
凶手会是谁呢？